3dcontentcentral.com 2019-06-06

# 3D ContentCentral - Free 3D CAD Models, 2D Drawings, and Supplier Catalogs

**3D ContentCentral** **®** ******Privacy Policy**

Dassault Systèmes SolidWorks Corporation ("DS SolidWorks") would like to thank you for using the 3D ContentCentral **®** **** online service. As you know, the 3D ContentCentral service provides a means for users to search and view from various perspectives CAD models in many different CAD formats. Users that register ("Registered Users") may also reconfigure, download, and upload a CAD model in many different CAD formats. The CAD models have been created by Registered Users and independent manufacturers ("Suppliers") who may also make them available via an online catalog. The 3D ContentCentral service also provides access to library features, blocks, and macros supplied by Registered Users for viewing and downloading by other users. We know Suppliers and users may have questions regarding the privacy of their interactions on [www.3DContentCentral.com](http://www.3dcontentcentral.com/) and hope this privacy policy will answer any questions you may have. If not, please contact us at the email address or postal address shown below.

**Using the 3D ContentCentral** **®** ** Service - No Anonymous Use Is Possible for Full Access**

For full access, you must register with DS SolidWorks to use the 3D ContentCentral service. In general, you must provide DS SolidWorks with your name, email address, street address, and certain profile information. If you do not provide this information, you will not be able to take full advantage of the 3D ContentCentral service (e.g., download certain models).

**The Use of Personal Data**

Personal data ("Personal Data") means any information that may result in the identification of an individual. Non-Personal Data means any information that does not result in the identification of an Individual.

DS SolidWorks may use the Personal Data you provide us for a variety of purposes, including authentication and marketing, and sharing for sales and marketing purposes the Personal Data with our parent company, Dassault Systèmes, and ours and its other affiliates ("DS Group"). DS SolidWorks may collect information such as number of visits, average time spent on the site, and pages viewed, and this information may be traceable back to you. DS SolidWorks uses this information to analyze how people use our service and to generate ideas on how the service might be improved.

We and our affiliates may also use your Personal Data to inform you of special offers, upgrades, and other DS Group products and services that may be of interest to you. Additionally, we may share the information you provided to us with the Suppliers whose content you access via 3D ContentCentral. We may also share your information with DS SolidWorks partners and other companies and organizations providing search capabilities on the website or other complementary services. We may also provide you with materials concerning the products and/or services of other third parties we think may be of interest to you.

DS SolidWorks may also disclose such Personal Data if required by law or if DS SolidWorks believes in good faith that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (such as a warrant, subpoena, or other court order) or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of DS SolidWorks, our customers or the public.

**Cookies**

Cookies are text files stored and used to record non-personal and personal information concerning your browsing of the site.

DS SolidWorks may use cookies or other technologies that may collect or store Personal Data to improve services for you through, for example:

  * enabling a service to recognize your device so you don't have to give the same information several times, 
  * recognizing that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do so repeatedly, 
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast, 
  * analyzing data to help DS SolidWorks understand how people interact with the Site so DS SolidWorks can improve the site. 

The 3D ContentCentral service uses a third party vendor to help measure and analyze the effectiveness of the website and how visitors use www.3DContentCentral.com. To do this, tracking techniques (e.g., cookies) are used to collect information, which may include the pages visited, when the pages are visited, other sites that have been visited prior to our site, and navigation patterns. This tool will collect the IP address and assign an anonymous identifier to it. Neither your name, username, nor password is collected by the tool and an anonymous identifier is used to uniquely identify you. We only use the tool for the purpose of learning how visitors use our site in order to make improvements to the site To prevent this website analysis tool from collecting your behavioral data, please edit your account preferences.

DS SolidWorks may use two types of cookies: permanent cookies and temporary cookies. Temporary cookies disappear as soon as you log off from the site. Permanent cookies remain after logging off from the site in order to be used on subsequent visits to the site.

DS SolidWorks' European sites will notify you the first time you receive a cookie, and then you decide whether to accept it or refuse it. By continuing to use the site in consideration of the above, you expressly authorize DS SolidWorks to use such cookies.

You can also configure your browser software to refuse all cookies; if you do so, however, some areas and features of the site may not function properly and/or you may not access some parts or services of the site.

You can set Your preferences here.

| 

**Personal Data Processing and Storage**

Processing of Personal Data includes using, storing, recording, transferring, adapting, summarizing, amending, reporting, sharing, and destroying Personal Data as necessary under the circumstances or as otherwise required by law.

All Personal Data that is collected will be stored for a duration that is relevant to the purpose of such collection and for so long as required by applicable law.

DS SolidWorks may maintain and process Personal Data directly or indirectly in one or more databases in the United States or elsewhere. We may hire other companies to provide services on our behalf that may involve the storage and use of your Personal Data. Any such company or third party is required to maintain the confidentiality of that information and is prohibited from using that information for any purpose other than as authorized by us. If you provide Personal Data to DS SolidWorks, you agree and consent to the storage and usage of your Personal Data by DS SolidWorks and its affiliates for a variety of purposes including those described herein.

**Protection of Personal Data Concerning Children**

DS SolidWorks products and services (other than SOLIDWORKS Apps for Kids, which is subject to a separate privacy policy), are not marketed to children under the age of 13 and DS SolidWorks does not knowingly collect, or store Personal Data from children under the age of 13. DS SolidWorks is committed to protecting the privacy of children and if DS SolidWorks becomes aware that such information was collected, it will treat that information as sensitive.

**Collecting Personal Data**

The information provided at this site is collected by Dassault Systemes SolidWorks Corporation, 175 Wyman Street, Waltham, Massachusetts 02451. Our telephone number is (781) 810-5011.

This website contains links to Supplier models owned and maintained by other companies. By downloading a Supplier model, you consent to sending your Personal Data to the company that owns the Supplier model or the Internet catalog services provider of that company, and you acknowledge that such collection of Personal Data will be subject to the privacy policies of the company that owns the Supplier model or the Internet catalog services provider of that company.

**Updating Personal Data and "Opting Out"**

DS SolidWorks wants to ensure that the information it collects is accurate. Please notify us of any change to your address, phone number, email address, or other information by sending us an email message at [privacy@solidworks.com](mailto:privacy@solidworks.com) or by notifying us in writing at:

Dassault Systemes SolidWorks Corporation  
175 Wyman Street  
Waltham, Massachusetts 02451  
Attn: Legal Department 

If at any time you wish to "opt out" of receiving information from DS SolidWorks and having your information further shared with our affiliates, our partners, and other companies (with the exception of Suppliers that own content you have downloaded via the 3D ContentCentral service as described), please notify us by sending us an email or written message at the respective address shown above. Please note that due to lead times on certain mailings and other contacts, you may continue to receive communications for a period following your "opt out" notification. 

If you do not wish your information to be shared with Suppliers, edit your contact preferences on www.3DContentCentral.com; however, you may no longer be able to access or use Supplier models via 3D ContentCentral. Furthermore, if you wish to "opt out" of receiving information from a Supplier whose Internet catalogs you have accessed, you will need to separately contact that Supplier and opt out of receiving information from that Supplier.

**Third Party Actions**

DS SolidWorks does not monitor nor control the acts and postings of the Suppliers and users of the 3D ContentCentral service and DS SolidWorks is not responsible for any actions of Suppliers, Users, or third parties.

**DISPUTE RESOLUTION**

Although DS SolidWorks has put in place reasonable safeguards to protect Personal Data, we recognize that there is no method of transmitting or storing Personal Data that is completely secure.

However, DS SolidWorks is committed to ensure the privacy of Personal Data. If you have a reason to believe that the security of your Personal Data has been compromised or misused, you should contact DS SolidWorks by sending an email to [privacy@solidworks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com).

DS SolidWorks will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints regarding use and disclosure of Personal Data in accordance with the principles contained in this Privacy Policy.

**Date of Entry into Force of the Privacy policy and Changes to it**

This Privacy Policy may be updated according to DS SolidWorks' requirements and circumstances, or when required by applicable laws and regulations. 

Revised: August 18, 2016
